Register of the World War I subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Booklet, "The Balfour Visit: How America Received Her Distinguished Guest; and the Significance of the Conferences in the United States in 1917," (Box-folder 25: 5)
- Booklet, "Belgium Under German Administration,", 1915 July (Box-folder 25: 6)
- Booklet, "Black List and Blockade: Interview with The Rt. Hon. Lord Robert Cecil, M.P. in Reply to the Swedish Prime Minister,", 1916 (Box-folder 25: 7)
- Booklet, "Britain's Case Against Germany: A Letter to a Neutral,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 8)
- Booklet, "The British Commonwealth of Nations,", 1917 May (Box-folder 25: 9)
  A speech made by General Smuts on 15 May 1917.
- Booklet, "The British Empire and A League of Peace: Suggesting the Purpose and Form on an Alliance of the English-Speaking Peoples,", 1919 (Box-folder 25: 10)
- Booklet, "The Case of the Allies: Being the Replies to President Wilson, and Mr. Balfour's Despatch,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 11)
- Booklet, "Censorship and Trade,", 1916 (Box-folder 25: 12)
- Booklet, "The Character of the British Empire,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 13)
- Booklet, "The Conflict for Human Liberty,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 25: 14)
- Booklet, "The Deportations: Statement by the American Minister to Belgium,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 15)
- Booklet, "England and Her Critics,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 16)
- Booklet, "Fête Nationale Belge/Belgian Independence Day/Belgische Onafhankelykheidsdag,", 1916 July (Box-folder 25: 17)
  Addresses delivered at the Royal Albert Hall by M. Hymans, the Right Honorable H.H. Asquith, and M. Standaert. In French, English and Dutch.
- Booklet, "The Fourth of July in London,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 18)
- Booklet, "A Free Future for the World,", 1916 November (Box-folder 25: 19)
  A speech by the Right Honorable H.H. Asquith, Prime Minister, at the Guildhall on 9 November 1916.
- Booklet, "Frightfulness in Retreat,", 1917 (Box-folder 25: 20)
- Booklet, "General Smuts's Message to South Wales,", 1918 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Booklet, "General Von Bissing's Testament: A Study in German Ideals,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Booklet, "The German Idea of Peace Terms,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- Booklet, "The German Note and the Reply of the Allies,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 4)
- Booklet, "Great Britain's Sea Policy: A Reply to an American Critic, reprinted from 'The Atlantic Monthly,'", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 5)
- Booklet, "Is England Apathetic? A Reply,", 1915 (Box-folder 26: 6)
- Booklet, "The Justice of Rumania's Cause,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 7)
- Booklet, "The Jutland Battle by Two Who Took Part in It,", 1916 (Box-folder 26: 8)
- Booklet, "The King of Hedjaz and Arab Independence,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 9)
- Booklet, "A Lasting Peace: A Conversation between X. (a neutral) and Y. (an Englishman),", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 10)
- Booklet, "The League of Nations: The Opportunity of the Church,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 26: 11)
- Booklet, "The League of Peace and a Free Sea,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 12)
- Booklet, "A List of Neutral Ships Sunk by the Germans from August 8, 1914 to April 26, 1917,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 26: 13)
- Booklet, "The Mails as a German War Weapon: Memorandum on the Censorship of Mails Carried by Neutral Ships,", 1916 (Box-folder 26: 14)
- Booklet, "Memorandum of the Belgian Government on the Deportation and Forced Labour of the Belgian Civil Population Ordered by the German Government,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 15)
- Booklet, "Microbe-Culture at Bukarest: Discoveries at the German Legation,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 16)
- Booklet, "My Mission to London, 1912-1914,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 26: 17)
  By Prince Lichnowsky, late German Ambassador in England.
- Booklet, "Naval Prospects in 1917," (Box-folder 26: 18)
- Booklet, "The Navy and the War (August, 1914 to August, 1915)," (Box-folder 26: 19)
- Booklet, "To Neutral Peace-Lovers: A Plea for Patience,", 1916 (Box-folder 26: 20)
- Booklet, "Parliament's Vote of Thanks to the Forces: Speeches Delivered in the Houses of Parliament, Westminster, on October 29, 1917," (Box-folder 26: 21)
- Booklet, "Peace: How to Get and Keep It,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 26: 22)
- Booklet, "Peace Proposals and the Attitude of the Allies,", 1916 December (Box-folder 26: 23)
  A speech by the Prime Minister, the Right Honorable D. Lloyd George, 19 December 1916.
- Booklet, "The Peace Terms of the Allies,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 24)
- Booklet, "Plain Words from America: A Letter to a German Professor,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 25)
- Booklet, "Savings Union Service,", 1918 March (Box-folder 26: 26)
- Booklet, "Shirking the Issue: A Letter to Dr. George Brandes,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 27)
- Booklet, "Six of One and Half-a-Dozen of the Other: A Letter to Mr. L. Simons of The Hague,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 28)
- Booklet, "The Union of Two Great Peoples,", 1917 August (Box-folder 26: 29)
  A speech by W. H. Page, LL.D., American Ambassador to England, delivered at Plymouth, 4 August 1917.
- Booklet, "The Voice of Ireland: Being an Interview with John Redmond, M.P. and some Messages from Representative Irishmen regarding the Sinn Fein Rebellion,", 1916 April (Box-folder 26: 30)
- Booklet, "The War on German Submarines,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 31)
- Booklet, "The War on Hospital Ships,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 32)
- Booklet, "The War Pantheon,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 26: 33)
- Booklet, "What Is England Doing?,", 1916 (Box-folder 26: 34)
- Booklet, "When the War Will End,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 35)
- Booklet, "The World's Largest Loan,", 1917 (Box-folder 26: 36)
- Booklet, "The Zeebrugge Affair,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 26: 37)
- Booklets, "Miscellaneous -- correspondence and reports presented to both Houses of Parliament,", 1916-1918 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  Includes "Miscellaneous No. 35 (1916): Further Correspondence Respecting the Proposed Release of Civilians Interned in the British and German Empires;" "Miscellaneous No. 1 (1917): Further Correspondence Respecting the Proposed Release of Civilians Interned in the British and German Empires;" "Miscellaneous No. 13 (1917): Reports on the Treatment by the Germans of British Prisoners and Natives in German East Africa;" "Miscellaneous No. 7 (1918): Report on the Treatment by the Enemy of British Prisoners of War Behind the Firing Lines in France and Belgium;" and "Miscellaneous No. 11 (1918): Correspondence with the Netherlands Government Respecting the Requisitioning of Dutch Ships by the Associated Governments."
- Leaflet, "A Brief Memorandum Relating to the War Between Gt. Britain and Germany: Why Is Great Britain at War?,", 1914 October 8 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- Leaflet, "Canada, and Its Place in the War,", 1914 November 17 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Leaflet, "Does the British Navy Take Prisoners?,", circa 1916 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Leaflet, "Free Belgium,", 1916 July (Box-folder 27: 5)
  Includes two copies of the issue (number 81) of this propaganda leaflet, one in English and one in French.
- Leaflet, "Last Will and Testament of the Pirate-Vulture,", circa 1914 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  Photocopy of a satirical version of Kaiser Wilhelm's will.
- Leaflet, "League of Neutral States: A Statement from the Dutch Section,", 1916 December 27 (Box-folder 27: 7)
- Leaflet, "A Letter from Satan to Kaiser Wilhelm,", 1917 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  Photocopy of a satirical article written by Louis Syberkrop of Creston, Iowa.
- Leaflet, "To the Workmen Affiliated to the Confederation General du Travail,", 1917 December 18 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  Published by the General Federation of Trade Unions.
- Booklet, "Annexe I aux Tables de tir du canon de 75 Mle 1897,", 1917-1918 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  Includes versions from 25 August 1917 and 12 April 1918.
- Booklets, Belleau Wood Memorial Association, circa 1923, 1927 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  Includes "Belleau Wood and the American Army, the 2nd and 26th Divisions (June and July 1918)" by Captain R. Andriot of the French Army, translated by W.B. Fitts, circa 1923; "The American Expeditionary Forces in the European Conflict: A Few Historic Dates and Facts," 1927; and a map of the Belleau Woods offensive, circa 1923 (in French).
- Booklet, "Carnegie Tech War Verse,", 1918 (Box-folder 27: 12)
- Booklet, "The 'Commission for Relief in Belgium' and the Chateau de Mariemont" and "Hôtes Américains a Mariemont pendant la première Guerre Mondiale,", 1973 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  From Cahiers de Mariemont, No. 4, 1973. In English and French.
- Booklet, "Defensive Measures Against Gas Attacks,", 1917 November (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Booklet, "Les Dons Américains,", 1918 (Box-folder 27: 15)
- Booklet, "History of the Medical Department of the Twenty-Eighth United States Infantry,", 1919 (Box-folder 27: 16)
- Booklet, "Hoover Overseas and War Service Organizations, 1914-1924: Address Register and Directory,", 1929 November (Box-folder 27: 17)
- Booklet, "How the Colored Race Can Help in the Problems Issuing from the War,", 1919 (Box-folder 27: 18)
- Booklet, "Jews and Germanism,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 27: 19)
- Booklet, "Notes on Recent Operations--No. 1,", 1918 August 7 (Box-folder 27: 20)
- Booklet, "Notice sur la recherche du Calibre des Obus Allemands,", 1916 September 10 (Box-folder 27: 21)
- Booklets, orders re awarding of medals, 1919 (Box-folder 27: 22)
  Consists of two sets of orders. One, published by the War Department, 11 March 1919, General Orders No. 37, names men awarded the distinguished-service cross (both living and those awarded it posthumously). The second, published by G.H.Q., American Expeditionary Forces, 3 June 1919, Citation Orders No. 4, names men entitled to wear a silver star on the Victory Medal ribbon.
- Booklets, "Publications of the Red Cross Institute for Crippled and Disabled Men,", 1918 (Box-folder 27: 23)
- Booklet, "The Relation of Earning Power to Award of Compensation for Disability Incurred in Military or Naval Service,", 1919 (Box-folder 27: 24)
  "A Memorandum on the Pensions Practice of Other Nations Prepared at the request of the Bureau of War Risk Insurance by the Red Cross Institute for Crippled and Disabled Men," by Douglas C. McMurtrie.
- Booklet, "Roster of Company 'I', 28th Infantry, First Division,", 1919 (Box-folder 27: 25)
- Booklet, "Section Data Book,", 1918 June (Box-folder 27: 26)
  Blank booklet issued to batteries of artillery by General Headquarters, American Expeditionary Forces.
- Booklet, "The Soldier's Progress,", 1918 (Box-folder 27: 27)
- Booklet, "Visit of the British Educational Mission to the United States,", 1918 (Box-folder 27: 28)
- Correspondence, Hoover Overseas and War Service Organizations, 1930 September 10 (Box-folder 27: 29)
  Letter to members in regards to the book American Food in the World War.
- Correspondence, Krehbiel, Edward B., 1915 (Box-folder 27: 30)
  Includes a 3 May 1915 letter to the Secretary of State regarding travel and the need for a passport; information from the State Department about passports and travel in Europe; and a partially completed passport application for Krehbiel and his family.
- Directory, American Expeditionary Forces, undated (Box-folder 28: 1)
  Provides A.P.O. numbers for the various services, divisions, and units of the American Expeditionary Forces.
- Form, Ausweis, 1919 June 21 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  Pass issued by the Kriegsministerium to members of the American Red Cross allowing them to travel to Paris and back. In German.
- Leaflet, "Elektrische Anlage,", undated (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Lyrics, French military songs, 1915, undated (Box-folder 28: 4)
  Includes "Les Zeppelins sur Paris," "Chanson des Tranchées de la Premiére Compagnie, (air marche des Cambrioleurs)," and "La Bochignole (air Carmagnole et Ça ira)," as well as a poem by Jean Richepin about the Kaiser.
- Newspaper, The Gangplank News, 1919 June 7 (Box-folder 28: 5)
- Newspaper clipping [photocopy], The Sun and New York Herald, "Red Cross Camera Men in Thrilling Adventures Abroad,", 1920 August 29 (Box-folder 28: 6)
- Program, "Die Wacht am Rhein,", circa 1919 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  "A musical comedy with a real plot; original and up-to-date in four scenes and two acts" written and produced by the First U.S. Engineers.
- Ration cards, France, 1919 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  Two sheets of bread ration cards for March and April 1919.
- Stamps, Russian propaganda, circa 1914-1915 (Box-folder 28: 9)
- Typescript, "The Artillery Information Service,", 1918 August (Box-folder 28: 10)
  Issued to Artillery Information Officers and to regimental and higher headquarters from General Headquarters, American Expeditionary Forces.
- Typescript, "Etat de Service du General de Division Blanchard du Cadre de Reserve,", post 1935 (Box-folder 28: 11)
- Typescript, "Rules and Regulations Governing Movement of Troops by Train,", 1918 March 5 (Box-folder 28: 12)
- Booklet, "Bringing Our Men Home,", circa 1919 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  Bulletin No. 3 of the War Commission of the Episcopal Church.
- Booklet, "Gold and Blue Stars Illustrated: 40 Thrilling Stories by Wounded Soldiers,", 1919 June (Box-folder 28: 14)
- Booklet, "The Old Glory Song Book: Our Best National Patriotic Songs,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 15)
  Inside is a program for a Twilight Forest Sing, 4 July 1918. Published by the Illinois State Register, Springfield, Illinois, copyright 1917.
- Booklet, "The Truth About Our Allies,", circa 1919 (Box-folder 28: 16)
  Reprinted from the University of California Chronicle, Volume XXII, No.1, this booklet includes addresses made at the University Meeting, 7 November 1919, by members of the First California Ambulance Unit: Paul F. Cadman, John Boardman Whitton, and Whitney Braymer Wright.
- Clippings, Facts and Fun, circa 1918 (Box-folder 28: 17)
  Includes both full pages and individual articles from Facts and Fun, which appears to be a publication of the Central Junior High School in Sangamon County, Illinois. There are poems, stories, and articles about the participation of students and the community in the war effort.
- Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 28: 18)
  Includes a postcard sent by a soldier of the U.S. Ambulance Service with the Italian Army (November 1918); appeals for relief (1917, 1919, 1920); a progress report sent from the Local Board for Division No. 3, Union County, New Jersey to the War Department (October 1918); and a letter from Braun & Company, an Alsatian art firm, to the President of Stanford about the business reopening (1920).
- Flyer, "Crush the Kaiser With Cash! Buy a Liberty Bond!,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 19)
  The reverse side advertises a "Monster Parade, Friday Eve., April 12th, 1918" in San Francisco.
- Flyer, "How Many Victory Notes Would You Be Willing to Buy If These Were German Bombs Falling on Your Home?,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 28: 20)
  The reverse side reads "Liberty Bonds Kept These From Being German Bombs - Victory Liberty Notes Pay for Peace." According to a handwritten annotation on one, it was dropped from an airplane during Fair Week in 1918.
- Leaflet, "Freedom of Oceans,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 28: 21)
  Article by Samuel W. Pennypacker, ex-Governor of Pennsylvania, reprinted from The Sun in a column titled "Food for the Thinker."
- Leaflet, "'Hey Fellows!' Your Money Brings the Book We Need When We Want It,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 22)
  Published as part of the United War Work Campaign by the American Library Association, detailing the work of the Library War Service.
- Leaflet, "Prayers,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 28: 23)
  Includes prayers for the World Family, for Victory, for our Men, for our Allies, for our Enemies, for the Women at Home, and more.
- Leaflet, song lyrics, circa 1930 January (Box-folder 28: 24)
  Compliments of Grinnell Bros. Music House in Detroit, Michigan. Includes such songs as "The Star-Spangled Banner," "Dixie," "America," and more.
- Leaflet, "Springfield News-Record Jr.,", 1919 January 1 (Box-folder 28: 25)
  Edited by and for the carriers of the News-Record in Springfield, Illinois.
- List, Norway, undated (Box-folder 28: 26)
  Appears to be referencing various materials about Norway.
- Music, "Have a Smile for Everyone You Meet and They Will Have a Smile for You,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 27)
- Music, "I'm Glad I Can Make You Cry,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 28)
- Music, "Little French Mother, Good Bye!,", 1919 (Box-folder 28: 29)
- Music, "The Navy Will Bring Them Back,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 30)
- Music, "Oh! How I Wish I Could Sleep Until My Daddy Comes Home,", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 31)
- Music, "Salvation Lassie of Mine,", 1919 (Box-folder 28: 32)
  The cover and first page of the lyrics and music are missing.
- Music, "Wee, Wee, Marie (Will You Do Zis For Me),", 1918 (Box-folder 28: 33)
- Newspaper clipping, "70,000,000 in Foodstuffs Sent to the Relief of Belgium,", undated (Box-folder 28: 34)
  Photostat of the second page of the article; the first page is not included.
- Newspaper clipping, New York Times, "World's Biggest Clipping Order Handled by the Argus Press Clipping Bureau,", 1926 March 22 (Box-folder 28: 35)
  Subheading of article: "Clippings on War Fill 400 Volumes. Gift by Rockefeller Assures Preservation for Historians of Press Collection."
- Newspaper clipping, San Francisco Examiner, "California Poet in Berlin Voices His Views on War,", 1915 October (Box-folder 28: 36)
  Subheading of article: "Herman Scheffauer Gives Pointed Opinions on the Conflict and Its Effect in Europe During Interview With Noted Writer." The story is by Franz Hugo Krebs.
- Printed matter, American Red Cross, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 28: 37)
  Includes Red Cross Christmas Roll Call enrollment forms; a receipt from the National War Finance Committee of the American Red Cross; a leaflet titled "Your Duty to the War Cripple;" a leaflet enclosing Red Cross Christmas Seals, as well as information about tuberculosis; and window posters indicating support of the Red Cross.
- Printed matter, Liberty Loans, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 28: 38)
  Includes posters for subscribers to the 4th Liberty Loan and the Victory Liberty Loan to put in their windows, as well as blank applications for the Victory Liberty Loan.
- Printed matter, United War Work Campaign, 1918 (Box-folder 28: 39)
  Includes a donation receipt, leaflet (about the work of the Y.M.C.A.), booklet (about the work of War Camp Community Service), and poster.
- Program, Christian Patriots' Convention, 1918 November (Box-folder 28: 40)
  Put on in Springfield, Illinois by the Laymen's Missionary Movement, 21 and 22 November 1918. Includes information about the convention, program of events, and brief biographical information about the speakers.
- Program, Community Thanksgiving for Victory and Peace, 1918 November 28 (Box-folder 28: 41)
  This event took place at the State Arsenal, Springfield, Illinois, under the auspices of the Federated Churches.
- Program, First Annual National Patriotic Sing, 1917 February 20 (Box-folder 28: 42)
  This event took place at the State Arsenal, Springfield, Illinois, under the auspices of the Civic Music Association.
- Tags, miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 28: 43)
  Includes a tag to tie on your coal shovel with tips for saving coal; Fatherless Children of France tags; and a Victory Boys tag.
- Typescript, "Escapes of Contrasting Kind,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 28: 44)
  By Alfred James Fritchey, Co. C, 3rd Machine Gun, Bn. 1st Div., telling his account of the Battle of Cantigny.
- Typescript, "Germany's Indemnity,", circa 1919 (Box-folder 28: 45)
  Scrap of paper with a few brief paragraphs, written by Lloyd Catron, comparing Germany to a wolf.
- Typescript, "Honors Paid First Three U.S. Soldiers Who Died in Battle on French Soil,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 28: 46)
- Booklet, "La Lanteren de Patachon,", 1914 November 19 (Box-folder 28: 47)
  Issue No. 3, by Jacques & La-Hüre.
- Booklet, "The War Cartoons of Louis Raemaekers,", 1917 (Box-folder 28: 48)
  Includes a biographical sketch of Raemaekers and 100 illustrations with descriptive notes.
- Booklet, "Why Britain Is in the War and What She Hopes From the Future,", 1916 October (Box-folder 28: 49)
  A speech by the Rt. Hon. Viscount Grey of Fallodon, Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, addressed to the Representatives of the Foreign Press in London on 23 October 1916.
- Collected materials, passports and passes, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 28: 50)
- Drawings, Hungarian political cartoons, undated (Box-folder 28: 51)
  Many of the cartoons feature Petar, a mustachioed man wearing a crown, fur, epaulets, and some military regalia. Other than the captions, the only other text printed at the bottom of each page appears to read "Minden jog fentartva. Kerlesz: Orczy-ut 10." In Hungarian.
- Flyers, Credito Italiano, 1917, undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
  Flyers urging Italians to subscribe to the Nuovo Prestito Nazionale Consolidato: "Sottoscrivete presso la Banca Italiana di Sconto."
- Flyers, Poland, 1915-1918, 1923, 1928 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  The majority of the flyers are honoring fallen soldiers and celebrating Poland and its victories.
- Flyer, "Vsiem'! Russkie grazhdane i soldaty!,", undated (Box-folder 29: 3)
  German appeal to Russian citizens to overthrow their government.
- Leaflets, Austria-Hungary war loans, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  Includes leaflets for the fourth and fifth Kriegsanleihe, as well as newspaper clippings related to the seventh Oesterreichische Kriegsanleihe.
- Leaflet, "Genossen, Soldaten des sich befreienden Deutschlands!,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  Russian propaganda in Germany published by Das Petersburger Comite der Russischen Kommunistischen Partei.
- Leaflets, "Lettres à tous les Français,", 1915-1916 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  Nos. 1-12, from circa December 1915 to April 1916. The publishing committee includes: Ernest Lavisse, President; Emile Durkheim, Secretary; Max Leclerc, Treasurer; and other professors and academics.
- Leaflet, "Der Völkerfriede,", 1918 January (Box-folder 29: 7)
  Russian propaganda in Germany published by the Organ der Internationalen Abteilung des Zentralkomitees der Arbeiter-, Soldaten- und Bauerndelegiertenräte.
- Music, "C'est encore la France!,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 29: 8)
- Music, "Les Chansons de la Grande Guerre 1914,", 1915 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  Seven leaflets, all with the same cover, but containing different songs (lyrics and music). The songs are: "Acte de Foi," "A coups de crosse," "Affaire est sûre (L')," "Cloche morte (La)," "Gamins de Paris (Les)," "Rêve de Soldat," and "Turco (Le)."
- Music, "Les Chansons de la Woëvre (Verdun, 1915),", 1916 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  Booklet includes nine songs (lyrics and music): "Lettre de Petit Pierre à Papa Noël," "Les Canaris de Verdun," "Fleurettes de Trianon," "Mimi Pinson met sa Cocarde," "Chanson à ma Mie," "Le Jardin du Gourbi," "La Lettre," "Octobre (1. 2.)," and "Nos Morts son vivants! (1. 2.)."
- Music, "Vers l'Aube de Gloire,", 1915 (Box-folder 29: 11)
- Printed matter, French, miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 29: 12)
  Includes a Bleuets flyer with associated imagery (the Bleuet being the symbol of memory for veterans and victims of war); and what appears to be the outer packaging of a set of note cards, "Bonnes Nouvelles des Poilus" (the note cards are not included).
- Booklets, "Am Lagerfeuer: Halbmonatsschrift für Heer und Marine,", 1918 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  Includes No. 13, 1 July, "In stiller Sommernacht;" No. 14, 15 July, "O lieb', solang du lieben kannst!;" and No. 15, 1 August, "Mein liebes Mutters."
- Booklets, "Eulen-Feldpost: Monatsschrift für die Mitglieder der Eule, Ortsgruppe Leipzig der A.V.d.B.G.,", 1915-1916 (Box-folder 29: 14)
  Includes No. 1, 15 September 1915, "Zum Geleit;" No. 2, 15 October 1915, "Die Aufnahme der Eulen-Feldpost;" No. 3, 15 January 1916, "Die uns mit ihrem Leibe decken;" No. 4, 15 March 1916, "Leipziger Allerlei;" No. 5, 20 April 1916, "Sie kämpfen;" No. 6, 30 May 1916, "Erfolge im Westen;" and No. 7, 11 June 1916, "Wann reift der Friede?."